JIN KUAN MOO

https://minahhh666.github.io/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/jin-kuan-moo/

Summary

A UCD Computer Science Master proficient in Chinese Mandarin, English, and Malay. Currently working as a computer lab demonstrator in UCD. Full stack development experience in several languages(Java, Spring Boot JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Python) as well as Agile methodology. Good experience understanding of algorithms and data structure. Great Git, DevOps(CI/CD pipeline), networking (TCP/IP), database(MySQL, NoSQL), OS(Linux, Windows), and cloud(AWS, GCP) knowledge. Experience with distributed systems, machine learning, Docker, and Containers. Previously worked as a manager in Ireland, leading a team of 20 engaged in daily production. Volunteered in Code in Place hosted by Stanford University, delivering online Python lessons to a group of 15 students. Great team player with decent communication skills.

Email: jkmoo0412@hotmail.com

Mobile: 0892059402

Technical Skills

- Programming languages: Python, JavaScript, Java, Ruby, HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Spring Boot, Bash, Astra
- Frameworks: React.js, Flask, Express.js, JavaFX, Pygame
- Database: MySQL, AWS RDS, NoSQL, MongoDB, Amazon S3
- OS: Linux, Windows
- Tools: Jupyter Notebook , Microsoft Office, WordPress
- DevOps: Jenkins, GitHub, Unit Testing, Apache Maven, Ansible, Terraform, Selenium
- Cloud: AWS EC2, AWS EMR, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes
- Distributed Systems: MapReduce, Hadoop, HDFS, Spark, Rest, RMI, RabbitMQ, Web Services, Akka
- Machine Learning: Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Random Forest, XGBoost, KNN, Scikit-learn
- Others: Data Structures and Algorithms, Networking (TCP/IP), OOP, CI/CD

Education

University College DublinDublin, IrelandMSc Computer Science; GPA:3.82 (First Class Honours)Sep 2022 – Dec 2023

Cornell UniversityExchange Programme; GPA:3.87 (First Class Honours)
Aug 2019 – Dec 2019

University College Dublin

BSc Food Science; GPA: 3.77 (First Class Honours)

Dublin, Ireland

Sep 2017 – Jun 2021

Projects

Foodie (Backend Developer)

a food delivery distributed system including functionalities like user accounts, order, restaurants, payment, and delivery.

- Java Spring boot is used as the backend framework along with the implementation of Akka actor to facilitate the communications in distributed systems
- A simplistic dashboard frontend is built using React and server sent events (SSE) to represent the real-time updates among the systems
- MongoDB used to store various data
- Docker is used for containerization, and Kubernetes is integrated to demonstrate its scalability
- GitHub used for version control, with unit tests and logging system in place to ensure integrity

Afterparty (Backend Developer, University Summer Internship)

an event impact analysis tool which provides insights into how the busyness of urban areas are impacted by large-scale event.

- Utilized React.js, Mapbox GL.js, and Figma for the frontend development
- Implemented the backend with Node.js, Express.js, Flask, and Apache
- Developed prediction models using Random Forest and XGBoost

Dublin Bikes (Full-Stack Developer)

a web application providing real-time information and journey planning for bike-sharing services.

• Utilized Vanilla JS, HTML, CSS, and Google Maps API for frontend development

- Implemented the backend with Flask, MySQL, AWS EC2, AWS RDS, Gunicorn, Nginx
- Developed prediction models using Linear Regression

Experience

University College Dublin

Dublin, Ireland

Computer lab demonstrator

January 2024 – Now

- Provide module support and assistance to Undergraduate and Master Computer Science students
- Data Analytics, Network & Internet System, Operating Systems, Distributed Systems

Freelancer

Dublin, Ireland

Web designer/ WordPress Frontend developer

Sep 2023 – Jan 2024

- Designing personal/commercial website for customers
- Experience in WordPress, Domain & Email Hosting, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Stanford UniversityDublin, IrelandPython TutorApr 2023 – Jun 2023

- Participating in Code in Place, an online introductory coding course
- Conducting weekly lessons for a cohort of 15 students
- Teaching topics including Python, Animations, Console Programming, Graphic Programming etc.

Krispy KremeManufacturing Manager
Sep 2021 – Jun 2022

- Managing a 20-member team for daily production operations
- Ensuring adherence to safety protocols, HACCP principles, and legal regulations
- Maintaining accurate inventory control, yield records, and traceability documents

Honours

- UCD Global Southeast Excellent Scholarship
- UCD Food Science Scholarship
- Kepak Best in Class Award